Ankita Hanamshet

Python Developer(Data Science)

Experienced Data Science resource adept at collecting, analyzing, and interpreting large datasets, developing models, and performing data management tasks. With 2 years of development experience and strong programming skills, I am currently looking for a Python Developer position with a forwardmoving company.



ankii7546@gmail.com

+91 98459 37057



in linkedin.com/in/ankita-h



github.com/ankita-hanamshet

EXPERIENCE

Python Developer(Data Engineer) Tata Consultancy Services

12/2021 - Present

Skills: Core Python, Python for Data Science, SQL, PySpark

Responsibilities

- Manipulating, processing and extracting value from large datasets.
- Working with relational databases, query authoring (SQL) as well as working familiarity with a variety of databases.
- Building and optimizing 'big data' data pipelines. architectures and data sets.
- Integration of data from multiple data sources
- Performing root cause analysis on internal and external data and processes to answer specific business questions and identify opportunities for improvement.

Java/IVR Developer Tata Consultancy Services

11/2020 - 12/2021 Skills: Core Java, SQL

Responsibilties

- Designing Call Flow based on customer requirement in Microsoft Visio
- Building a web-based IVR application from scratch using Java in CISCO Call Studio
- Performing SQL operations required for the working of IVR application in SQL developer
- ICM script changes based on requirements

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

Basaveshwar Engineering College

08/2016 - 09/2020

CGPA: 8.65/10

Courses

 Computer Science and Engineering

SKILLS

Python

Machine Learning (Supervised, Unsupervised)

Python for Data Science(Numpy, Pandas)

Dashboard (Tableau, Power BI)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Machine Learning Predictive Model on BigMart Sales Data

Built a predictive model to predict the sales of each product at a particular outlet. Using this model, BigMart will try to understand the properties of products and outlets which play a key role in increasing

Machine Learning Classification Model on Credit Card Default Prediction

This project aims at predicting the case of customers default payments. From the perspective of risk management, the result of predictive accuracy of the estimated probability of default will be more valuable. Classification models are designed for the prediction.

Machine Learning Regression Model on Bike Sharing **Demand Prediction**

 Currently Rental bikes are introduced in many urban cities for the enhancement of mobility comfort. It is important to make the rental bike available and accessible to the public at the right time as it lessens the waiting time. Regression models are designed to predict the bike count required at each hour for the stable supply of rental bikes.

Exploratory Data Analysis on Play Store App Review Analysis.

The Play Store apps data has enormous potential to drive app-making businesses to success. Actionable insights can be drawn for developers to work on and capture the Android market. Analyzed data to discover key factors responsible for app engagement and success.

TRAININGS

Data Science Trainee (04/2022 - Present) AlmaBetter

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

Kannada Marathi